

I am Finnish, English, and Swedish speaking, a high-performing sales professional with more than 10 years of experience from B2B and B2C sales, new business development, and marketing. I excel in account management, new customer acquisition, upselling, and closing deals.

I am experienced in designing and setting up team-wide sales processes and pipelines. While working in the insurance industry I have also been involved with product management and product development experience.

I have an analytical mindset, and as a professional athlete, I am consistent, systematic, solution oriented, and have remarkable time management skills. My excellent verbal and written communication skills allow me to explain complex products and services in a simple manner, both in person, on a phone, or using digital channels.

EXPERIENCE

Turva / Lähitapiola, mutual insurance

Jan 2023 – Present

Sales representative

Helsinki, Finland

- Top 5% sales-performing sales representative, consistently exceeded sales targets by 25%
- Assured long-term revenue recurrence and contract profitability by focusing on profitable portfolio
- Aligned all the key stakeholders in every proposal, sales, revenue management, contracts and operations
- Collaborated with senior management and got their commitment to expand our product portfolio
- Maintained relationships with cooperation companies and organisations such as trade unions
- New customer acquisition, outbound
- Cold calling, lead qualification, risk analysis, sales negotiation, closing deals, upselling, customer relationship
- Maintained + growed existing client accounts
- Handled a wide variety of customer, mainly Finnish and English speaking customers

IF, insurance Jan 2016 – Dec 2022

Sales representative

Helsinki, Finland

- Top 10% sales-performing sales representative, consistently exceeded sales targets by 20%
- New customer acquisition, outbound
- Focused on larger private customer sector
- Cold calling, lead qualification, risk analysis, sales negotiation, closing deals, upselling
- Sales face to face, phone, other digital channels
- Participated in various events as a company representative

Fennia, mutual insurance

Dec 2014 - Dec 2015

Business development representative

Espoo, Finland

- Launched new business unit in Sello, Leppävaara
- Recruited to expand Fennia's business to private customer market within a new area
- Reached the goal to increase Fennia's market share by 5%
- Negotiated new contracts for cooperation with companies and organisations for quality leads
- Set up sales processes, trained and onboarded team of sales professionals
- Analysed and continuously developed sales processes
- Runned pilots for new sales channels, such as booking concept and promotion team
- Handled daily face to face meetings
- Closing deals

IF, insurance Jan 2014 - Dec 2014

Sales manager, corporate insurance

Helsinki, Finland

- New customer acquisition, outbound
- Cold calling, lead qualification, sales negotiations face to face meetings, customer relationships.
- Participated in various events for new leads, such as seminars and event for entrepreneurs in Helsinki,
 Tallinn and Stockholm

Sales, private insurance. Outbound + inbound sales and prospecting.

Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

A project office where working according to the project's various needs in the industry. Later on assigned to focus mainly on sales.

- Integration of Trygg insurance company's insurances
- Piloting the latest products
- Piloting the cooperation with Nordea bank
- New customer acquisition, negotiating new contracts, closing deals

Sales and marketing manager, Clubhouse Incanto

Jan 2008 - Dec 2010

- Responsible for health and wellness centre's sales and marketing
- Campaign planning and execution
- Sales goal setting for the sales team

EDUCATION

Metropolia, open University

September 2024- Present

Information Technology

- Microsoft Azure fundamentals
- Ms Project software
- Power BI
- Python programming
- Artificial Intelligence with Python

NL College, Language school

April 2024- Present

• Spanish

Proacademy, University of Tampere

Aug 2021 - May 2023

Master's degree, Entrepreneurship and leadership

Tampere, Finland

Jan 2010 - Jul 2013

• Scholarship to Geneva for international studies at 2022 autumn

Laurea University of Applied Sciences

Bachelor's Degree, Business Administration, Management and Operations

Espoo, Finland

Universidad Europea de Madrid

Bachelor's Degree, Business Administration, Management and Operations

Aug 2011 - Aug 2012 Madrid, Spain

LANGUAGES

Finnish Native

English Fluent working proficiency / Bilingual

Spanish Basic Swedish Basic

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Professional Athlete, Fitness

2013 - Present

High-performance athlete on Fitness Sports (Nordic championships top 10, Finnish Nationals top 6). Invited to Arnold's Classic, Madrid 2022

Skydiver 2003 - 2020

Current holder of Finnish record of formation skydiving (Prague 2017). Skydiving instructor for advanced students Skydiving athlete in a 4-way formation skydiving team (FS formation skydiving league top 3, Finnish Nationals top 3).

2008 - 2015